<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SeaX API Wiki on Seasalt.ai API Documentation</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/</link><description>Recent content in SeaX API Wiki on Seasalt.ai API Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Refeactored SeaX Multi-Channel Messaging API Wiki (Refactored)</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/refactored/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/refactored/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The SeaX Multi-Channel Messaging API is a comprehensive communication platform that enables businesses to integrate and automate messaging across SMS, WhatsApp, and voice channels. Built for scalability and enterprise use, SeaX provides unified tools for multi-channel campaigns, contact management, and conversational workflows across all major messaging platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="supported-channels">Supported Channels&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#supported-channels" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="-sms--mms-messaging">📱 SMS &amp;amp; MMS Messaging&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#-sms--mms-messaging" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bulk SMS Campaigns&lt;/strong>: Send text messages to large contact lists&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>MMS Support&lt;/strong>: Share images, videos, and rich media content&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Two-Way Messaging&lt;/strong>: Receive replies and engage in SMS conversations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delivery Reports&lt;/strong>: Track message delivery status and engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="-whatsapp-business-platform">💬 WhatsApp Business Platform&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#-whatsapp-business-platform" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rich Media Messages&lt;/strong>: Send images, documents, videos, and audio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Template Messages&lt;/strong>: Use pre-approved templates for notifications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interactive Messages&lt;/strong>: Buttons, lists, and quick reply options&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business API Compliance&lt;/strong>: Full WhatsApp Business API integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Highly Structured Messages (HSM)&lt;/strong>: Certified template messaging&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="-voice--phone-calls">📞 Voice &amp;amp; Phone Calls&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#-voice--phone-calls" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Auto Dialer Campaigns&lt;/strong>: Automated outbound call campaigns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Custom Call Scripts&lt;/strong>: Dynamic call flows and interactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interactive Voice Response (IVR)&lt;/strong>: Menu-driven call handling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Call Recording&lt;/strong>: Record and analyze call interactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Callback Management&lt;/strong>: Handle inbound calls and callbacks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="key-features">Key Features&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#key-features" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unified Contact Management&lt;/strong>: Manage contacts across all channels from one platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Multi-Channel Campaigns&lt;/strong>: Coordinate messaging across SMS, WhatsApp, and voice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Advanced Analytics&lt;/strong>: Track performance metrics across all channels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Webhook Integrations&lt;/strong>: Real-time notifications for all channel events&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Template Management&lt;/strong>: Consistent messaging templates across channels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conversation Threading&lt;/strong>: Unified conversation views across channels&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication">Authentication&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#authentication" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SeaX API uses API key authentication. To obtain your API key:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seasalt.ai Analytics API</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/analytics/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Generate Metric Report endpoint provides a unified interface for retrieving
multiple analytics metrics in a single request, streamlining the process of
generating comprehensive reports for workspace performance analysis. Unlike
individual metric endpoints, this bulk endpoint allows you to request multiple
analytics types simultaneously, reducing API calls and improving efficiency for
dashboard and reporting applications. The endpoint supports all available
analytics metrics including conversation overviews, activity trends, label
usage, communication volumes, and detailed breakdowns, making it ideal for
creating unified analytics dashboards and comprehensive performance reports.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seasalt.ai Webhook Notification API Tutorial</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/webhook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/webhook/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A webhook-based notification system that lets your services receive real-time
updates from Seasalt.ai products like SeaChat. Whether you want to track new
conversations, missed calls, or contact changes, using the following endpoints
ensures you stay informed the moment it happens. With support for multiple event
types and delivery modes (immediate, delayed, batched), SeaX&amp;rsquo;s Webhook
Notification are ideal for diverse automation and integration needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One powerful use case built on top of this webhook system is our Zapier
integration. When an event is emitted via webhook, it can immediately trigger a
Zap, allowing users to seamlessly connect Seasalt.ai products with tools like
Google Sheets, Notion, Slack, and more. In this setup, webhooks act as the
upstream event source, and Zapier serves as the downstream automation engine,
consuming those events and turning them into custom workflows without any code.
Explore the integration here:
&lt;a href="https://zapier.com/apps/seasaltai/integrations">Seasalt.ai on Zapier&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bulk SMS/MMS Campaigns</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/bulk_sms_tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/bulk_sms_tutorial/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bulk-smsmms-campaigns">Bulk SMS/MMS Campaigns&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#bulk-smsmms-campaigns" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Bulk SMS/MMS Campaigns API enables you to send messages at scale to targeted contact lists. This comprehensive guide covers contact management, campaign creation, and monitoring. The API supports SMS, MMS, and WhatsApp Business Platform messages with advanced targeting, scheduling, and delivery tracking capabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading through this tutorial, try out the endpoints
&lt;a href="https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/docs/seax-api/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="authorization">Authorization&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#authorization" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You must provide your API key in the &lt;code>X-API-KEY&lt;/code> header.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WhatsApp Business Platform Campaigns</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/whatsapp_business_platform_campaigns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/whatsapp_business_platform_campaigns/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="whatsapp-business-platform-campaigns">WhatsApp Business Platform Campaigns&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#whatsapp-business-platform-campaigns" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The WhatsApp Business Platform Campaigns API empowers organizations to design and implement effective messaging campaigns targeting contacts on WhatsApp. By leveraging this platform, businesses can engage their audience on a widely-used messaging app, increasing open rates and enhancing customer interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-benefits">Key Benefits&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#key-benefits" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wider Reach&lt;/strong>: Connect with billions of users worldwide.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personalization&lt;/strong>: Customize messages to maximize engagement.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rich Media&lt;/strong>: Send images, videos, and documents.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Automation&lt;/strong>: Schedule and automate messaging workflows.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="use-cases">Use Cases&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#use-cases" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Product Promotions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customer Feedback Campaigns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Announcements and Updates&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="limitations">Limitations&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#limitations" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Requires a verified business account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limited to contacts who have opted-in.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After reading through this tutorial, try out the endpoints
&lt;a href="https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/docs/seax-api/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WhatsApp Business Platform General Campaigns API Tutorial</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/wabp_general_campaigns_tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/wabp_general_campaigns_tutorial/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="whatsapp-business-platform-general-campaigns-api-tutorial">WhatsApp Business Platform General Campaigns API Tutorial&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#whatsapp-business-platform-general-campaigns-api-tutorial" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>/api/v1/workspace/{workspace_id}/general_campaigns/wabp&lt;/code> endpoint allows
you to send WhatsApp Business Platform (WABP) template messages to multiple
destinations in a single API call. This is ideal for sending highly structured
messages using approved WhatsApp templates with personalized parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-features">Key Features&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#key-features" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Template-based Messaging&lt;/strong>: Send messages using pre-approved WhatsApp
templates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Multi-destination Support&lt;/strong>: Send to multiple recipients in one request&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Parameter Substitution&lt;/strong>: Personalize messages with dynamic parameters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Language Support&lt;/strong>: Use templates in different languages&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#prerequisites" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before using this endpoint, ensure you have:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Auto-Dialer Voice Campaigns</title><link>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/auto_dialer_voice_campaigns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://api.seasalt.ai/seax/auto_dialer_voice_campaigns/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="auto-dialer-voice-campaigns">Auto-Dialer Voice Campaigns&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#auto-dialer-voice-campaigns" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Auto-Dialer Voice Campaigns endpoint enables automated placement of bulk
outbound voice calls to selected contact lists, supporting both AI-powered
conversational agents and pre-recorded voice drops. Through a structured
configuration interface, users can define campaign parameters such as target
groups, call scripts, scheduling windows, and fallback behaviors. The endpoint
facilitates scalable voice outreach by handling call queuing, delivery tracking,
and engagement logging. Each campaign instance generates detailed execution
metrics and outcomes, enabling real-time monitoring and performance analysis.
Secure access to campaign operations requires authentication via API key. Below
we will cover the endpoints needed to customize, create, and monitor your own
voice call campaigns. Note: in this tutorial we are assuming you have configured
a phone number, contacts, and AI agents in your workspace.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>